Previously on
Space Brothers
むった
＜不運に縁がある 兄･六太｡➡
Older brother Mutta is plagued by bad luck.
ひびと
栄光の日生まれの弟･日々人は
日本人初のﾑｰﾝｳｫｰｶｰとなった｡➡
Born under a lucky star, younger brother Hibito becomes the first Japanese moonwalker.
月面望遠鏡建設を望む恩師･
シャロンとの約束を果たすため➡
Older brother Mutta seeks to become an astronaut, and keep his promise to former teacher Sharon,
to build a telescope on the moon.
兄･六太は宇宙飛行士を目指す｡➡
Mutta's made it through the first round, but he keeps running into trouble.
選抜試験を辛うじて突破するが
訓練中もトラブルの連続｡➡
On the written test, he scores the lowest.
筆記試験では最低点｡暴走教官が
飛行訓練の担当になる始末｡➡
And as a result, he's assigned to a wild flight instructor.
However, the older brother Mutta
だが 困難にもまれたおかげで
宇宙飛行士の大事な資質を➡
has yet to realize that he's rapidly learning the lessons he'll need to become an astronaut.
猛スピｰドで身に付けていることに
兄･六太は まだ気づいていない＞
Sharon's letters began coming less often.
なんば
＜次第にその数を減らしていった
シャロンからの手紙｡➡
月へ行く訓練を始めたって
堂々と言えたら➡
If I can tell her that I've started training for the moon...
ちょっとぐらい
シャロンの希望にならねえかな＞
Maybe that would be enough to give Sharon a little hope...
＜月の訓練への道を開くには➡
If I want to start training for lunar missions,
結局 バトラー室長に
認めてもらうしかない＞
I have to get Chief Butler to agree...
自分を一人前のﾊﾟｲﾛｯﾄと感じたのは
いつですか？って問いに➡
The question was, "When did you first feel that you were a pilot?"
And astronaut Jason Butler's answer was...
宇宙飛行士になったジェーソン･
バトラーは こう答えている｡
⦅バーティカルクライムロールを
教官の前で披露した時だ⦆
When I first performed the vertical climb roll before my instructor.
で 私にそのバーティカルクライム
ロールを教えてくれと｡
You want me to teach you the vertical climb roll?
必要なんだよ 意思の表れとして！
I need to learn the maneuver to express my resolve.
You're going to perform it for the chief?
(ｱﾚｯｸｽ)室長に見せる気かい？
君は実に…無謀な男だね｡
You're a crazy guy...
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)ああっ！…まさか！
It can't be!
1 Hour Earlier
(ｱﾚｯｸｽ)よりによって
何でマックス号なの？
Why are you taking Max up?
実に不可解だね｡
命が惜しくないのかい ムッタ｡
That baffles me.
Are you trying to throw your life away, Mutta?
こんなデニール仕様の荒馬で
アクロバットするなんて｡
You want to do acrobatics in this monster of Deneil's?
Nah, if I pull off the maneuver in this baby...
こいつで技を決めてこそさ｡
"You're a real top gun."
一流じゃねえか ハハハ！
…って言われるような
気がするからさ｡
That's what he'll probably say.
It's just obvious that the more you put in your bag
The heavier it gets
The harder I work, the closer I get to my goal
But I'm just not getting there fast enough
I gaze at the night sky but it doesn't calm me down
Now that you've heard how loud my heart's beating
Let's take a trip outside
My starvation knows no bounds under this sea of stars
In this planetarium of dreams and reality
I'm currently updating the canvas of my dreams
With a glittering universe and a blue earth
My starvation knows no bounds under this sea of stars
In this planetarium of facades and honesty
I'm currently conversing with the canvas of my dreams
On this orbit of fate
With a fire in my belly
#75 My Hands
ウホホッ！怖いよ～！感度が
良すぎるんだよ コイツは｡➡
I'm so scared!
This plane is too sensitive.
I just nudged it a millimeter.
ミリ単位で この反応だぞ｡➡
デニールは よく
あのぶっとい指で➡
How was Deneil able to control this joystick with those chubby fingers?
そうじゅうかん
こんな繊細な操縦桿を
握ってたもんだ｡
小さい動きでｺﾝﾄﾛｰﾙできるように
改造したんじゃない？
Maybe he modified it so he could control the plane with minimal movement?
Since he's so lazy.
ズボラだから｡
(ｱﾚｯｸｽ)おっと 時間だ ムッタ｡
操縦をかわろう｡
Oh, it's time, Mutta...
I'm giving you control.
Roger that!
了解！この技を
室長が見ててくれたら…➡
If the chief sees me pull it off,
フフフ 一体どうなるか！
what will happen then?
(ｱﾚｯｸｽ)怒られるんじゃない？
宇宙飛行士が➡
You'll probably get in trouble?
He'll say that an astronaut shouldn't waste time on this nonsense.
何 余計なことやってんだって｡
T-5!
５秒前…４…３…２…１！
4!
3!
2!
1!
バーティカルクライムロール
レッツゴー！
Vertical climb roll...
Let's go!
Come on, now...
おっ…ううっ!!
ウヒョーッ！
Woo-hoo!
あの…申し訳ない｡
Excuse me, I'm sorry...
少しばかりエーリントン飛行場で
降ろしてもらえますか｡
Could you drop me off at Ellington Airport for a moment?
Okay!
よ～し！次は１８時３３分開始！
例のヤツね｡
The next one begins at 6:33 PM.
I'm doing the other one.
Okay!
(ｱﾚｯｸｽ)ＯＫ！
今日の訓練で｢エーリントンの
飛行場に着いたら➡
The e-mail said it would happen at 6:33 PM, after we arrived at Ellington Airport for training.
１８時３３分に｣ってメールで｡
(北村)｢空を見て｣って？
You're supposed to look at the sky?
Uh-huh.
うん｡２５分には
着いてるはずだったんだけど…➡
We were supposed to arrive at 6:25,
but the shuttle was running late...
まさかシャトルバスが遅れるとは｡
これじゃ間に合わないよね｡
We won't make it in time.
What does he want to show Serika?
《何を見せる気なんだろ？
せりかちゃんに》
Could Nanba be planning something with fireworks?
《まさか南波君
花火的な何かで…》
A message in the sky?
《みたいなことを!?キャーッ！》
せりか 席をかわりましょ｡
ここからならきっと見えます｡
Serika, let's switch seats.
You should be able to see it from here.
ありがとう アマンティ｡
Thank you, Amanti.
Amanti...
《アマンティ すでに何かが
見えているのね あなたには…》
You already know what's coming, huh?
I'll be right back.
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)すぐに戻ります｡
Yes, hello? This is Butler.
あ～ もしもし バトラーだ｡➡
さっきバーティカルクライム
ロールをやったＴ-３８➡
Tell me who's in the T-38 that just performed a vertical climb roll.
誰が乗ってるか教えてくれ｡
訓練生は ナンバ･ムッタです｡
同乗の教官は➡
The trainee pilot is Nanba Mutta.
The instructor accompanying him is Alexander Nikolas Phillipos Medina—
アレクサンダー･ニコラス･
フィリッポス･メディナカロス｡
ＯＫ わかった｡
Okay, got it.
Nanba Mutta...
ナンバ…ムッタ…｡
It seems we won't arrive at the airport in time...
《やっぱり間に合わないか…
飛行場》
さ～あ 次 行くぞ～！
Okay! Time for the next one!
⦅空にハートマークでも描けりゃ
ひとまず一人前だ⦆
If you can draw a heart in the sky, you're qualified.
《今度は せりかさん➡
It's Serika's turn.
Watch this...
見ててくれよぉ～》
If you ensure your sweetheart is watching,
⦅意中の女にでも
披露してみろ⦆
you stand a good chance of getting your girl.
⦅かなりの確率で
イチコロだぞ ハハハ！⦆
ハートマーク レッツゴー！
Heart in the sky...
Let's go!
Get the girl!
イーチーコロー!!
あっあれかな？
Oh?
Is that it?
ああ～っ！スゴーイ！
That's amazing!
南波さん！
Nanba!
すごいな～｡でも何だろう？あれ｡
It's amazing...
But I can't tell what it is.
よく分かんないけど
すごいアクロバットだね！
I don't know what it's supposed to be, but those were fancy acrobatics!
Yes.
そうね…｡
《あ…あれは…》
I-Isn't that...
Hmm? Th-Th-Th-This is...
う…こここ…これは…｡
ど どういうことだね！
ミスター･ムッタ｡
Wh-What is the meaning of this, Mr. Mutta?
ヒャッホー！決まった～！
Yahoo! I pulled it off!
(ｱﾚｯｸｽ)イヤッホー！ハハハ！
Yahoo!
ま まさか…これだったのか!?
私に見せたいものって！
D-Don't tell me that this is what he wanted to show me?!
Th-That isn't good!
そ それは…マズイでしょ～!!
ｴｺｰ マズイでしょ～!!
室長！
うっは～！
Chief!
昨日のあれ 見てもらえましたか!?
Were you watching yesterday?
U-Uh...
い いやぁ まあ 一応 見たよ｡
Ah, well... Yes, I was watching.
あれが僕の
伝えたかった気持ちです!!
That was my way of expressing my feelings!
ブホー！
Please let me participate in lunar mission training!
どうか！僕にも月の訓練を！
わ わかった！➡
O-Okay... I'll think about it!
考えておく 考えておくから
ちょっと離れなさい！
I'll consider it, so back off!
いや 離れません！
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)離れなさい！
No, I refuse.
Back off!
離れません！
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)は は 離れなさい！
I refuse.
B-Back off!
離れません！
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)離れないのぉ～！
I refuse.
You refuse?
《よし！これでいいんだ｡
室長の心へ一歩 歩み寄った》
Good, that should do it...
I managed to leave a lasting impression on the chief.
《でも…昨日のハートマークは
惜しいことしたな～》
But I screwed up the heart in the sky...
⦅南波さ～ん！⦆
⦅せりかさん！⦆
Nanba!
Serika!
⦅さっきの見えましたよ！
スゴイですね！⦆
I saw you up there.
That was amazing...
Y-Y-You saw it?
⦅う…み 見てもらえましたか？⦆
⦅バルタン星人ですよね!?あれ⦆
⦅あ いや～その…え～っ！⦆
It was an Alien Baltan, right?
Yeah, it was a...
Eh?!
《ハートを描いたつもりが
バルタン星人になっていたとは》
My heart turned into
an Alien Baltan?
俺も まだまだだな～｡
I still have work to do...
(ﾓﾘｿﾝ)ハァハァハァーフゥー｡
(田村)遠いところ よく お越し
くださいました｡➡
Thank you for making the trip out here...
モリソン博士｡
(ﾓﾘｿﾝ)シャロン博士は？
Dr. Morrison.
Where is Dr. Sharon?
(田村)先生は奥に…｡
The professor is in the back.
ん～ はい できました｡
ありがとう｡
Okay, all done!
Thanks.
Wow! You're way better at this than Mom!
おぉ～！母ちゃんより
数倍 うまいね！ヒヒー｡
は～い 次 俺～｡
All right, I'm next!
お客さん 今日はどういう感じで？
What would you like today, sir?
Make it spiky!
ツンツンにしてください！
It's already spiky.
すでにツンツンだろ｡
ふふ…かしこまりました｡
As you wish.
ムッちゃん｡
Mu...
Huh?
Give me some!
俺にも ちょうだい！
ふふ～ん｡
You're really good with your hands, Aunt Sharon.
おばちゃんの手ってさあ
器用だよね｡
ピアノも弾けるし➡
You can play the piano and cut hair.
さんぱつ
散髪 上手だし
この手作りクッキーも➡
And the cookies you bake are better than the ones my mom buys.
母ちゃんが好きで買って来る
ヤツより数倍うまいよ｡
そうなの？うふふ ありがと｡
Really?
Thank you.
自慢の手ね｡
I like my hands.
《私は この両手で わが子を
抱き上げることはなかった｡➡
I never got to hold my own child with these hands...
オムツを換えてあげたり➡
I never got to change diapers or feed my baby...
ごはんを食べさせてあげる
経験も できなかった｡➡
だから今 このひととき
くらいは母親の手でありたい》
So, for this moment, I want my hands to be those of a mother.
現在
(田村)先生｡
Professor?
モリソン博士が
お見えになりました｡
Dr. Morrison is here to see you.
(ｹﾘｰ)ようこそ｡➡
Welcome.
I'm Kelly, Sharon's sister.
シャロンの妹のケリーです｡
どうぞ よろしく｡
Please make yourself at home.
モリソンです｡こっちは一番
下っ端の助手レオナルド｡
I'm Morrison.
This is Leonard, my youngest assistant.
ウチの博士がお世話になってます｡
Your sister has been a big help.
I'll go get my sister.
姉を連れてきますね｡
お座りになって お待ち下さい｡
Please have a seat while you wait.
妹さんも美人ですよ 博士｡
よかったっすね｡
Her sister's also pretty, Professor.
Aren't you lucky?
お前は だまっちょれ！
You shut your mouth!
(ｼｬﾛﾝ)遠いところ ありがとう
ございます モリソン博士｡
Thank you for coming such a long way, Dr. Morrison.
It's fine... I've come to fulfill my promise.
いえ…約束を果たしに…｡
⦅ぜひ我々も協力させて
いただきますよ⦆
We will offer what assistance we can.
計画の引き継ぎなんて
無理なお願いをして➡
Asking you to take over the project for me was unreasonable.
本当に ごめんなさい｡
モリソン博士｡
I'm very sorry, professor.
とんでもない｡
もとより協力するつもりで➡
Don't be...
I'd planned to assist by reaching out to friends and acquaintances from my college days.
大学時代からの友人知人に
広めてましたよ｡
月面望遠鏡計画｡
For the lunar telescope...
これは集まった協力者の名簿です｡
This lists the people who've agreed to help.
Every day, we're adding names.
今でも広がり続けてますよ
我々だけでなく｡
This isn't our dream...
みんなの夢として｡
ありがとうございます｡
It's everyone's dream.
Thank you very much.
その後 体の具合はどうですか？
How have you been doing?
(ｼｬﾛﾝ)ええ｡手も足もずいぶん
弱くなってきて➡
Ah...
My arms and legs have gotten weaker.
手書きの文字は ちょっと➡
And now, I'd be too embarrassed to show you my handwriting.
お見せできない
有様になってしまいました｡
タッチパネルの操作や
キーボードを打つくらいなら➡
I can still use touch screens and keyboards,
まだ出来るので
もう少し仕事は出来そうですが➡
so I can continue working...
いつ動かせなくなるか…｡
But at some point, I will be unable to move.
(ﾓﾘｿﾝ)シャロン博士の
夢の部分にならば➡
I believe that we can contribute to your dream.
多少の貢献も出来るでしょう｡
我々の両手を
使ってくださればいい｡
Please use our hands.
レオナルド｡
はい？
Leonard...
Yes?
この先 彼女の病気が
どう進行してゆくか➡
Do you remember when I told you about how her disease will progress?
前に話したのを憶えてるな｡
はい｡
Yes.
(ﾓﾘｿﾝ)実現させるぞ！
We're going to make this happen!
Sharon!
姉さん 何やってるの？
ダメよ ハサミなんて｡
What are you doing?
You shouldn't use scissors...
刃物は危ないわよ｡
Using sharp objects isn't safe for you.
スクラップとかなら
私がやってあげるから｡
I can cut clippings for your scrapbook.
うん もう今日は寝るわね｡
Yes.
Then, I'm going to bed.
Oh?
おやすみ姉さん｡
おやすみ｡
Goodnight.
Goodnight...
もう…ダメなんだ…｡
It's over...
⦅はい これで
クッキーの型をとります⦆
Here, you use these cookie cutters to make them.
Wow, that looks fun.
⦅うお！面白そ！⦆
⦅星の形にロケットの型もある⦆
We can make star and rocket cookies!
A jam session?
⦅セッション!?⦆
⦅そう３人で楽器演奏するの⦆
Yes, all three of us will play together.
Congratulations, Mutta!
⦅おめでとうムッタ
凄いじゃない⦆
⦅いや～それほどでも⦆
That's amazing...
Nah, it's no big deal.
Hey, Aunt Sharon, show me how to do this.
⦅ねぇシャロンおばちゃん
ここ教えて！⦆
⦅私が２人の先生ってわけね⦆
I guess that makes me your teacher.
⦅あら どちら様？⦆
⦅あの…はっはじめまして⦆
Oh? Who might you be?
Uh, nice to meet you.
Happy birthday, Aunt Sharon!
(２人)⦅シャロンおばちゃん
誕生日おめでとう！⦆
I can no longer do any of the things...
今までのこと何もかも➡
もう…出来ないんだ…｡
I once could.
ムッタへ あなたが月に行ける頃➡
Dear Mutta...
By the time you reach the moon,
私は あなたと話せなく
なっているかもしれません｡
I may not be able to speak to you.
そうなる前に
月面望遠鏡設置の流れを➡
Before that happens,
I will record the instructions for building the lunar telescope.
ここに記録しておきます｡
もちろん➡
I'm well aware that astronauts may not always receive the missions they request.
誰もが希望するミッションに
むね
任命されるわけではない旨➡
承知しています｡
All done!
できた～！
(ﾋﾟｰﾀｰ)ああ余裕だな｡
(ダン)試作品第一号！完成！
Yeah, that was easy.
Our first prototype is finished!
Yay! We did it!
ワオ！
(ダン)やった～｡
Wonderful!
素晴らしい！
(ﾋﾟｰﾀｰ)グッジョブ｡
Good job!
Mr. Nanba...
(ビンス)ミスターナンバ｡
だけど きっとあなたが➡
But I have faith that you will be there to hear this message.
これを聞いてくれると信じて…｡
ついて来て下さい｡
そろそろ始まります｡
Please come with me.
It's time to begin.
え？な 何がですか？
Huh?
Wh-What's about to begin?
これから君は➡
It's time to begin
月を目指します｡
your journey to the moon.
It's been so long since I looked up at the moon
Though it's always keeping a cold eye on me
Yeah, it always keeps a cold eye on me
I wanna rough up this rotten way home
But even if it makes me mad
I can't take my eyes off it. Yeah, I can't take my eyes off it
I can't take my eyes off that dazzling smile
What did I want back then?
What was I looking for?
I should've known my tears would take me to my dreams
Blow this gloomy reality away for me
I want to see how tiny our huge worries seem
From up in that dark ocean of space
Next time, on
Space Brothers
#76 Olga
I finally begin the rehabilitation in Russia.
＜ついに ロシアでの
リハビリ訓練が始まる＞
Say hello, Olga...
(ｲｳﾞｧﾝ)＜挨拶しろ オリガ｡➡
This is Nanba Hibichov.
こちらは 宇宙飛行士仲間の
ナンバ･ヒビチョフさん＞
Next time, on Space Brothers:
"Olga"
(オリガ)＜ばやいよ ヒビトだ＞
Wow, it's Hibbit...
Mr. Hibbit!
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰｲｰｸﾞﾙ)ゴホン！
よくぞこれだけの仲間を
見つけたなヒビット｡
You've done well to assemble all these crew members.
I am very happy!
ワシは いや私は嬉しいぞ｡
Yay!
(ﾋﾋﾞｯﾄ)イエーイ！じゃあ月へ
行っていいんだね｡
Can I go to the moon now?
いや まだ駄目だ｡
No, not yet.
Eh?!
You haven't trained together yet.
まだ君たちはメンバー全員で
訓練をしていないだろう｡
月へ行くには
チームワークが必要なのだ！➡
When going to the moon, teamwork is important!
Now, you will begin training!
さぁ～訓練に行くんだ｡
Your guide is waiting outside.
外に君たちの案内役を
待たせてある｡
あれ～誰もいないじゃん｡
Huh? I don't see anyone.
(ﾓｸﾞﾌｧｰ)や～っと来たの
あんたら｡
Took you guys long enough to get here.
遅いわね～待ちくたびれて
寝ようかと思ってたわ｡
Man, I was about to fall asleep, waiting for you...
Wh-Who's there?
(ﾊﾞﾃﾞｨｺﾞﾘﾗ)だ 誰だ！
誰もいニャいのに声が!?
Where is that voice coming from?
This must be a disembodied spirit, Devil Mouse.
これは姿なきオバケ➡
｢デビルマウス｣かも｡
オバケ!?やだ やだ やだ｡
A ghost?
No way, I don't like ghosts!
オバケやだ｡バナナがいい！
I like bananas!
It seems someone else is out here.
我々以外に何者かがいるのは
確かだ｡私は鼻が利く｡
I have a sharp nose.
ヒビット！足元を見るんだ｡
Hibbit, look down!
うわぁ～あらら～何だこれ！
Wow!
Oh? What's this?
(ﾓｸﾞﾌｧｰ)ど～こ見てんのよ｡
ココよココ｡
Where are you looking?
Over here.
Stare.
(一同)ジロ｡
えぇ！はっ…？
ハーイ！
Hi...
ちょっと動かないでくれる？
私は日差しが嫌いなのよ！
Hey, could you move?
I don't like sitting in the shade.
君は誰だい？
私はモグファーよ｡
Who are you?
I'm Moleifer.
Chief Butler Eagle asked me to help train you...
あんたらの訓練の
手伝いをするよう➡
バトラーイーグル室長から
頼まれてるわ｡
まずはこれから あんたらの➡
I'll start you off with some stamina-building exercises.
体力作りの訓練を
始めていくわけだけど➡
Anyone have any questions?
なんか質問ある人いる？
は～い！ニンジン食べる？
Yep! Want some carrots?
ハンバーガーなら もらうわ｡
I'll take a hamburger.
See you next week!